out the structure of a neural network
神经网络的结构
I'll give a quick recap here
我在这里简单总结一下
just so that it's fresh in our minds
只是为了让我们记忆犹新
and that I have two main goals for this video
我对这个视频有两个主要目标
the first is to introduce the idea of gradient descent
首先是引入梯度下降的思想
which underlies not only how neural networks learn
这不仅是神经网络学习的基础
but how a lot of other machine learning works as well
但是许多其他机器学习也是如何工作的
then after that
然后在那之后
we're going to dig in a little more
我们要再挖一点
to how this particular network performs
这个特定网络的表现
and what those hidden layers of neurons
那些隐藏的神经元层
end up actually looking for
最终真正寻找
as a reminder
作为提醒
our goal here is
我们在这里的目标是
the classic example of handwritten digit recognition
手写数字识别的经典例子
the hello world of neural networks
神经网络的Hello World
these digits are rendered on a 28 by 28 pixel grid
这些数字在28 x 28像素的网格上呈现
each pixel with some grayscale value between 0 and 1
每个像素的灰度值在0到1之间
those are what determine the activations of
这些是决定激活的
784 neurons in the input layer of the network
网络输入层的784个神经元
and then
然后
the activation for each neuron in the following layers
以下层中每个神经元的激活
is based on a weighted sum
是基于加权和
of all the activations in the previous layer
在前一层中的所有激活中
plus some special number called a bias
加上一些叫做偏差的特殊数字
then you compose that sum with some other function
然后你用其他函数组成这个总和
like the Sigmoid squishification or array loop
就像Sigmoid压扁或阵列循环一样
the way that I walked through last video
我看最后一个视频的方式
in total given the somewhat arbitrary choice of
总的来说，考虑到有点武断的选择
two hidden layers here
这里有两个隐藏层
with 16 neurons each
每个神经元有16个
the network has about
网络大约有
13 thousand weights and biases that we can adjust
1.30万我们可以调整的权重和偏差
and it's these values that determine
正是这些价值观决定了
what exactly the network
网络到底是什么
you know actually does
你知道实际上是这样的
then what we mean when
那么我们的意思是什么时候
we say that this network classifies a given digit
我们说这个网络对给定的数字进行分类
is that the brightest of those
那是其中最亮的吗？
10 neurons in the final layer
最后一层有10个神经元
corresponds to that digit
对应那个数字
and remember the motivation that we had in mind here
记住我们心中的动机
for the layered structure
对于分层结构
was that maybe
那是不是
the second layer could pick up on the edges
第二层可能会在边缘拾起
and the third layer might pick up on patterns
第三层可能会发现模式
like loops and lines
就像循环和线条
and the last one could just piece together
最后一个可以拼凑起来
those patterns
那些图案
to recognize digits
识别数字
so here we learn how the network learns
所以在这里我们学习网络是如何学习的
what we want
我们想要的
is an algorithm where you can show this network
是一个算法，你可以显示这个网络
a whole bunch of training data
一大堆训练数据
which comes in the form of a bunch of different images
它以一堆不同图像的形式出现
of handwritten digits
手写数字
along with labels for what they're supposed to be
以及它们应该是什么的标签
and it'll adjust those
它会调整这些
13 thousand weights and biases
1.30万权重和偏差
so as to improve its performance on the training data
从而提高其对训练数据的性能
hopefully
满怀希望地
this layered structure will mean that what it learns
这种分层结构意味着它所学习的
generalizes to images beyond that training data
泛化到训练数据之外的图像
and the way we test that is that
我们测试的方法是
after you train the network
在你训练网络之后
you show it more labeled data
你给它看更多的标记数据
that it's never seen before
这是前所未有的
and you see how accurately
你看有多准确
it classifies those new images
它对那些新图像进行分类
fortunately for us
对我们来说幸运的是
and what makes this such a common example
是什么让这成为一个如此常见的例子
to start with
首先
is that the good people behind the emnis database
是emennis数据库背后的好人
have put together
把
a collection of tens of thousands of handwritten
数以万计的手写收藏
digit images each one
每个数字图像
labeled with the numbers that they're supposed to be
标有他们应该是的数字
and as provocative as it is
虽然很有煽动性
to describe a machine as learning
将机器描述为学习
once you actually see how it works
一旦你真正看到它是如何工作的
it feels a lot less like some crazy SCI fi premise
感觉不像是什么疯狂的科幻小说
and a lot more like
更像是
well a calculus exercise
嗯，微积分练习
I mean basically it comes down to finding the minimum
我的意思是基本上它归结为找到最小值
of a certain function
具有某种功能
remember conceptually
概念记忆
we're thinking of each neuron as being connected
我们认为每个神经元都是相连的
to all of the neurons in the previous layer
到前一层中的所有神经元
and the weights in the weighted sum
以及加权和中的权重
defining its activation
定义其激活
are kind of like the strengths of those connections
有点像这些联系的力量
and the bias
和偏见
is some indication of whether that neuron tends to be
是神经元是否倾向于
active or inactive
活跃或不活跃
and to start things off
并开始事情
we're just going to initialize all of those weights
我们将初始化所有这些权重
and biases totally randomly
并且完全随机地偏差
needless to say
不用说
this network is going to perform pretty horribly
这个网络会表现得非常糟糕
on a given training example
在给定的训练示例上
since it's just doing something random
因为它只是随机做一些事情
for example you feed in this image of a 3
例如，您输入3的这张图片
and the output layer it just looks like a mess
输出层看起来一团糟
so what you do is you define a cost function
你要做的就是定义一个代价函数
a way of telling the no
一种说不的方式
bad computer that output should have activations
输出的坏电脑应该有激活
which are 0 for most neurons
对于大多数神经元来说是0
but one for this neuron
但是这个神经元有一个
what you gave me is utter trash
你给我的完全是垃圾
to say that a little more mathematically
从数学的角度来说
what you do is add up
你所做的就是加起来
the squares of the differences between each of those
它们之间差异的平方
trash output activations
垃圾输出激活
and the value that you want them to have
以及你希望他们拥有的价值
and this is what we'll call the cost
这就是我们所说的成本。
of a single training example
单个训练示例
notice this sum is small
请注意，这个金额很小。
when the network confidently classifies the image
当网络自信地对图像进行分类时
correctly
正确地
but it's large
但它很大。
when
什么时候
the network seems like it doesn't really know what
网络似乎真的不知道是什么
it's doing
它正在做
so then what you do is consider the average cost
所以你要做的是考虑平均成本
over all of the tens of thousands of training examples
在数以万计的训练示例中
at your disposal
任你处置
this average cost
这个平均成本
is our measure for how lousy the network is
是我们衡量网络有多糟糕的标准
and how bad the computer should feel
以及电脑应该感觉有多糟糕
and that's a complicated thing
这是一件复杂的事情
remember how
记得如何
the network itself was basically a function
网络本身基本上是一个功能
one that takes in 784 numbers as inputs
输入784个数字作为输入的数字
the pixel values
像素值
and spits out 10 numbers as its output
并吐出10个数字作为输出
and in a sense
从某种意义上说
it's parameterized by all these weights and biases
它被所有这些权重和偏差参数化了
well the cost function is a layer of complexity
代价函数是一层复杂性
on top of that
除此之外
it takes as its input
它将其作为输入
those 13,000 or so weights and biases
那一万三千左右的权重和偏差
and it spits out a single number
它吐出一个数字
describing how bad those weights and biases are
描述这些权重和偏见有多糟糕
and the way it's defined
以及它的定义方式
depends on the network's behavior
取决于网络的行为
over all the tens of thousands of pieces of training
在数以万计的训练中
data
数据
that's a lot to think about
要考虑的事情太多了
but just telling the computer
但只是告诉电脑
what a crappy job it's doing
这是多么糟糕的工作
isn't very helpful
不是很有帮助
you want to tell it
你想说出来
how to change those weights and biases
如何改变这些权重和偏见
so that it gets better
这样就会好起来
to make it easier
让它更容易
rather than struggling
而不是挣扎
to imagine a function with 13,000 inputs
想象一个有13,000个输入的函数
just imagine a simple function
想象一个简单的函数
that has one number as an input
有一个数字作为输入
and one number as an output
和一个数字作为输出
how do you find an input
你如何找到输入？
that minimizes the value of this function
最小化此函数的值
calculus students will know that
微积分学生会知道的
you can sometimes figure out that minimum explicitly
你有时可以明确地算出最小值
but that's not always feasible
但这并不总是可行的
for really complicated functions
对于非常复杂的功能
certainly
当然
not in the 13,000 input version of this situation
不在这种情况的13,000输入版本中
for our crazy complicated neural network cost function
我们疯狂复杂的神经网络代价函数
a more flexible tactic is to start at any all input
更灵活的策略是从任何所有输入开始
and figure out which direction you should step
并弄清楚你应该走哪个方向
to make that output lower
降低输出
specifically
具体地说
if you can figure out the slope of the function
如果你能算出函数的斜率
where you are
你所在的地方
then shift to the left if that slope is positive
如果斜率为正，则向左移动
and shift the input to the right
并将输入向右移动
if that slope is negative
如果斜率是负的
if you do this repeatedly
如果你反复这样做
at each point
在每一点
checking the new slope and taking the appropriate step
检查新斜坡并采取适当的步骤
you're going to approach
你要接近
some local minimum of the function
函数的一些局部最小值
and the image you might have in mind here is a ball
你们可能会想到一个球
rolling down a hill
滚下山坡
and notice
并注意到
even for this really simplified single input function
即使对于这个真正简化的单输入函数
there are many possible valleys that you might land in
你可能会在许多山谷着陆
depending on which random input you start at
取决于您从哪个随机输入开始
and there's no guarantee
也不能保证
that the local minimum you land in is
你降落的当地最低限度是
gonna be the smallest possible value of the cost
将是成本的最小值
function
函数
that's gonna carry over to our neural network case
这将延续到我们的神经网络案例中
as well and I also want you to notice how
我也想让你注意到
if you make your step sizes proportional to the slope
如果你让步长与斜率成正比
then
然后
when the slope is flattening out towards the minimum
当斜率向最小值变平时
your steps get smaller and smaller
你的脚步越来越小
and that kind of helps you from overshooting
这可以帮助你避免过度使用。
bumping up the complexity a bit
稍微提高一下复杂性
imagine instead
想象一下
a function with two inputs and one output
一个有两个输入和一个输出的函数
you might think of the input space as the XY plane
您可能会将输入空间视为XY平面
and the cost
和成本
function as being graphed as a surface above it
作为它上面的表面绘制的功能
now instead of asking about the slope of the function
现在不要问函数的斜率
you have to ask
你必须问
which direction should you step in this input space
你应该在这个输入空间中走哪个方向？
so as to decrease the output of the function
从而减少函数的输出
most quickly
最快
in other words what's the downhill direction
换句话说，下滑的方向是什么？
and again
又一次
it's helpful to think of a ball rolling down that hill
想想球从山上滚下来是有帮助的
those of you familiar with multi variable calculus
熟悉多变量微积分的人
will know that the gradient of a function
会知道函数的梯度
gives you the direction of steepest ascent
给你最陡峭的上升方向
basically which direction should you step
基本上你应该朝哪个方向走
to increase the function most quickly
以最快的速度增加功能
naturally enough taking the negative of that gradient
很自然地取梯度的负数
gives you the direction to step
给你前进的方向
that decreases the function most quickly
这会最快地降低功能
and even more than that
甚至更多
the length of this gradient vector
这个梯度向量的长度
is actually an indication for just how steep
实际上表明了有多陡峭
that steepest slope is
最陡的斜坡是
now if you're unfamiliar with multivariate
如果你不熟悉多元
calculus and you want to learn more
微积分，你想了解更多
check out some of the work that I did for Khan Academy
看看我为Khan学院做的一些工作
on the topic honestly though
老实说，在这个话题上
all that matters for you and me right now
现在对你我来说最重要的
is that in principle
原则上是这样吗？
there exists a way to compute this vector
有一种方法可以计算这个向量
this vector
这个向量
that tells you what the downhill direction is
这告诉你下坡的方向是什么
and how steep it is
以及它有多陡峭
you'll be okay
你不会有事的
if that's all you know and you're not
如果你只知道这些而你不是
rock solid on the details
细节坚如磐石
because if you can get that
因为如果你能得到那个
the algorithm for minimizing the function
最小化函数的算法
is to compute this gradient direction
就是计算这个梯度方向
then take a small step downhill
然后走下坡路
and just repeat that over and over
一遍又一遍地重复
it's the same basic idea for a function that has
这与具有
13,000 inputs instead of two inputs
13,000个输入而不是两个输入
imagine organizing
想象组织
all 13,000 weights and biases of our network
我们网络的所有13,000个权重和偏差
into a giant column vector
变成一个巨大的列向量
the negative gradient of the cost function
代价函数的负梯度
is just a vector
只是一个向量
it's some direction
这是一个方向
inside this insanely huge input space
在这个疯狂的巨大输入空间中
that tells you which nudges to all of those numbers
它会告诉你哪些数字会轻推到所有这些数字
is going to cause the most rapid decrease to the cost
将导致成本的最快下降
function
函数
and of course with our specially designed cost function
当然还有我们特别设计的代价函数
changing the weights and biases to decrease it
改变权重和偏差以减少它
means making the output of the network
意味着进行网络的输出
on each piece of training data
每一份训练数据
look less like a random array of 10 values
看起来不像10个值的随机数组
and more like an actual decision
更像是一个实际的决定
that we want it to make
我们希望它做的
it's important to remember
记住这一点很重要
this cost function involves an average
这个代价函数包括一个平均值
over all of the training data
所有的训练数据
so if you minimize it
所以如果你最小化它
it means
它的意思是
it's a better performance on all of those samples
在所有这些样本上都有更好的表现
the algorithm for computing this gradient efficiently
有效计算该梯度的算法
which is effectively
这是有效的
the heart of how a neural network learns
神经网络学习方式的核心
is called back propagation
称为反向传播
and it's what I'm going to be talking about next video
这就是我下一个视频要谈论的
there I really want to take the time to walk through
在那里我真的很想花时间走过
what exactly happens to each weight and each bias
每个重量和每个偏差到底会发生什么
for a given piece of training data
对于给定的训练数据
trying to give an intuitive feel for what's happening
试图给人一种直观的感受正在发生的事情
beyond the pile of relevant calculus and formulas
在一堆相关的演算和公式之外
right here right now
现在就在这里
the main thing I want you to know
我想让你知道的主要事情
independent of implementation details
独立于实施细节
is that what we mean
这就是我们的意思吗？
when we talk about a network learning
当我们谈论网络学习时
is that it's just minimizing a cost function
它只是最小化代价函数
and notice one consequence of that is that
请注意其中的一个后果是
it's important for this cost function to have a nice
这个代价函数有一个很好的
smooth output
平滑输出
so that we can find a local minimum
这样我们就可以找到局部最小值
by taking little steps downhill
通过走下坡路
this is why by the way
这就是为什么顺便说一句
artificial neurons
人工神经元
have continuously ranging activations
持续激活
rather than simply being active or inactive
而不是简单地活跃或不活跃
in a binary way
以二进制方式
the way that biological neurons are
生物神经元的方式
this process of repeatedly nudging
这种反复轻推的过程
an input of a function
函数的输入
by some multiple of the negative gradient
负梯度的倍数
is called gradient descent
叫做梯度下降
it's a way to converge towards some local minimum
这是一种收敛到局部极小值的方法
of a cost function
代价函数
basically a valley
基本上是一个山谷
in this graph
在这张图表中
I'm still showing the picture of a function
我还在展示一个函数的图片
with two inputs
有两个输入
of course because nudges in a 13
当然，因为轻推13
thousand dimensional input space
千维输入空间
are a little hard to wrap your mind around
有点难让你放心
but there is actually a nice
但实际上有一个不错的
non spatial way to think about this
以非空间的方式思考这个问题
each component
每个组件
of the negative gradient tells us two things
负梯度告诉我们两件事
the sine of course
当然是正弦
tells us
告诉我们
whether the corresponding component of the input vector
输入向量的对应分量是否
should be nudged up or down
应该向上或向下轻推
but importantly
但重要的是
the relative magnitudes of all these components
所有这些分量的相对大小
kind of tells you which changes matter more
告诉你哪个变化更重要
you see in our network
你看在我们的网络里
an adjustment to one of the weights
对其中一个权重的调整
might have a much greater impact on the cost function
可能会对代价函数产生更大的影响
than the adjustment to some other weight
而不是调整到其他重量
some of these connections just
其中一些联系只是
matter more for our training data
对我们的训练数据更重要
so a way that you can think about this gradient vector
所以你可以考虑这个梯度向量的一种方法
of our mind warpingly massive cost function
巨大的代价函数
is that
那是
it encodes the relative importance of each weight
它编码了每个权重的相对重要性
and bias that is
偏见就是
which of these changes is going to carry the most
这些变化中哪一个将带来最大的影响？
bang for your buck
一报还一报
this really is just another way of thinking about
这真的只是另一种思考方式
direction to take a simpler example
方向举个更简单的例子
if you have some function with two variables
如果你有一些具有两个变量的函数
as an input and you compute
作为输入，你计算
that its gradient at some particular point
它在某个特定点的梯度
comes out as 3 1
显示为3 1
then on the one hand
那么一方面
you can interpret that as saying that
你可以理解为说
when you're standing at that input
当你站在输入端时
moving along this direction
沿着这个方向移动
increases the function most quickly
最快增加功能
that when you graph the function above
当你绘制上面的函数时
the plane of input points
输入点平面
that vector is what's giving you the straight
这个向量就是给你直线的东西
uphill direction
上坡方向
but another way to read that
但另一种解读方式
is to say that changes to this first variable
就是说第一个变量的变化
have three times the importance
有三倍的重要性
as changes to the second variable
作为对第二个变量的更改
that at least in the neighborhood of the relevant input
至少在相关输入的附近
nudging the x value
轻推x值
carries a lot more bang for your buck
对你来说有更多的好处
all right
好吧
let's zoom out and sum up where we are so far
让我们缩小并总结一下我们目前所处的位置
the network itself is this function
网络本身就是这个功能
with 784 inputs and 10 outputs
具有784个输入和10个输出
defined in terms of all of these weighted sums
根据所有这些加权总和定义
the cost function is a layer of complexity
代价函数是一层复杂性
on top of that
除此之外
it takes the 13 thousand weights and biases as inputs
它将1.30万权重和偏差作为输入
and spits out a single measure of lousyness
然后吐出一个粗鲁的度量
based on the training examples
基于培训示例
and the gradient
和梯度
of the cost function is one more layer of complexity
代价函数的另一层复杂性
still it tells us what nudges to all of these weights
它仍然告诉我们是什么推动了所有这些权重
and biases cause the fastest change
偏见导致最快的变化
to the value of the cost function
代价函数的值
which you might interpret as saying
你可能会理解为说
which changes to which weights matter the most
哪个变化对哪个权重最重要
so when you initialize the network with random weights
所以当你用随机权重初始化网络时
and biases and adjust them many times
和偏差并多次调整它们
based on this gradient descent process
基于这个梯度下降过程
how well does it actually perform
它的实际性能如何？
on images that it's never seen before
在它从未见过的图像上
well the one that I've described here
嗯，我在这里描述的那个
with the two hidden layers of 16 neurons
有16个神经元的两个隐藏层
each chosen mostly for aesthetic reasons
每一个都主要是出于美学原因而选择的
well it's not bad
嗯，还不错。
it classifies about 96
它分类大约96
percent of the new images that it sees correctly
它正确看到的新图像的百分比
and honestly if you look at some of the examples
老实说，如果你看看一些例子
that it messes up on
它搞砸了
you kind of feel compelled to cut it a little slack
你觉得有必要放松一下
now if you play around with the hidden layer structure
现在如果你玩弄隐藏层结构
and make a couple tweaks
并进行一些调整
you can get this up to 98 percent
你可以把这个提高到98%。
and that's pretty good
这很好。
it's not the best
这不是最好的
you can certainly get better performance
你肯定能得到更好的表现
by getting more sophisticated than this plain
通过变得比这更复杂
vanilla network
香草网络
but given how daunting the initial task is
但考虑到最初的任务有多艰巨
I just think there's something incredible about
我只是觉得有些不可思议的东西
any network doing this
任何这样做的网络
well on images that it's never seen before
在它从未见过的图像上
given that we never specifically told it
鉴于我们从未明确告知过
what patterns to look for
要寻找什么模式
originally the way that I motivated this structure
最初我激发这个结构的方式
was by describing a hope
是通过描述一个希望
that we might have
我们可能有
that the second layer might pick up on little edges
第二层可能会出现小边缘
that the third layer would
第三层会
piece together those edges to recognize loops
拼凑这些边缘以识别循环
and longer lines
和更长的线
and that those might be pieced together to recognize
这些可以拼凑在一起来识别
digits so is this what our network is actually doing
数字，这就是我们网络实际在做的吗？
well
井
for this one at least not at all
至少这个一点也不
remember how last video we looked at
还记得我们上次看的视频吗？
how the weights of the connections
连接的权重如何
from all of the neurons in the first layer
从第一层的所有神经元中
to a given neuron in the second layer
到第二层的给定神经元
can be visualized as a given pixel pattern that
可以可视化为给定的像素图案
that second layer neuron is picking up on
第二层神经元正在接收
well when we actually do that
当我们真正这样做的时候
for the weights
为了重量
associated with these transitions
与这些转变相关
from the first layer to the next
从第一层到下一层
instead of picking up on isolated little edges
而不是捡起孤立的小边缘
here and there
这里和那里
they look well
他们看起来不错
almost random
几乎是随机的
just with some very loose patterns in the middle there
只是中间有一些非常松散的图案
it would seem that
似乎
in the unfathomably large
在深不可测的大
13,000 dimensional space of possible weights
13,000个可能权重的维度空间
and biases
和偏见
our network found itself a happy little local minimum
我们的电视网找到了一个快乐的小地方
that despite successfully classifying most images
尽管成功地对大多数图像进行了分类
doesn't exactly pick up on the patterns that we might
并没有完全发现我们可能发现的模式
have hoped for
希望
and to really drive this point home
为了真正阐明这一点
watch what happens when you input a random image
观察输入随机图像时会发生什么
if the system was smart
如果系统很智能
you might expect it to either feel uncertain
你可能会期望它要么感到不确定
maybe
也许吧
not really activating any of those 10 output neurons
没有真正激活这10个输出神经元中的任何一个
or activating them all evenly
或者均匀地激活它们
but instead
但相反
it confidently gives you some nonsense answer
它自信地给你一些胡说八道的答案
as if it feels as sure that this random noise is a 5
好像感觉这个随机噪音是5
as it does that an actual image of a 5 is a 5
因为5的实际图像是5。
phrase differently
短语不同
even if this network can recognize digits pretty well
即使这个网络可以很好地识别数字
it has no idea how to draw them
它不知道如何绘制它们
a lot of this is because
这在很大程度上是因为
it's such a tightly constrained
这是一个如此严格的约束
training setup
培训机构
I mean put yourself in the network's shoes here
我是说设身处地为电视网着想
from its point of view
从它的角度来看
the entire universe consists of nothing
整个宇宙什么也不是
but clearly defined
但定义明确
unmoving digits centered in a tiny grid
以小网格为中心的不动数字
and its cost function
和它的代价函数
just never gave it any incentive to be anything
只是从来没有给它任何动力去做任何事情
but utterly confident in its decisions
但对自己的决定充满信心
so if this is the image of what those second layer
所以如果这是第二层的图像
neurons are really doing
神经元真的在做
you might wonder why I would introduce this network
你可能想知道我为什么要介绍这个网络
with the motivation of picking up on edges
带着拾起边缘的动机
and patterns
和模式
I mean that's just not at all what it ends up doing
我的意思是，这根本不是它最终的结果。
well
井
this is not meant to be our end goal
这不是我们的最终目标
but instead a starting point
而是一个起点
frankly this is old technology
坦率地说，这是旧技术
the kind researched in the 80s and 90s
80年代和90年代研究的那种
and you do need to understand it
你确实需要理解它
before you can understand more detailed
在你能更详细地了解之前
modern variants
现代变体
and it clearly is capable of solving
它显然有能力解决
some interesting problems
一些有趣的问题
but the more you dig into what those
但是你越深入那些
hidden layers are really doing
隐藏层真的在做
the less intelligent it seems
看起来越不聪明
shifting the focus for a moment
转移一下焦点
from how networks learn to how you learn
从网络如何学习到您如何学习
that'll only happen
那只会发生
if you engage actively with the material here somehow
如果你以某种方式积极参与这里的材料
one pretty simple thing that I want you to do
我想让你做一件很简单的事
is just pause right now
现在只是暂停一下
and think deeply for a moment
深思片刻
about what changes you might make to this system
关于你可能会对这个系统做什么改变
and how it perceives images
以及它如何感知图像
if you wanted it to better pick up on things like
如果你想让它更好地了解诸如
edges and patterns
边缘和图案
but better than that
但比这更好
to actually engage with the material
实际接触材料
I highly recommend the book by Michael Nielsen
我强烈推荐迈克尔·尼尔森的书
on deep learning and neural networks
深度学习与神经网络
in it you can find the code and the data
在里面你可以找到代码和数据
to download and play with for this exact example
下载并播放此确切示例
and the book will walk you through step by step
这本书会一步一步地引导你
what that code is doing
该代码在做什么
what's awesome is that this book is free
厉害的是这本书是免费的
and publicly available
并公开提供
so if you do get something out of it
所以如果你确实从中得到了什么
consider joining me
考虑加入我
in making a donation towards Nielsen's efforts
为尼尔森的努力捐款
I've also linked a couple other resources that I like
我还链接了一些我喜欢的其他资源。
a lot in the description
描述中有很多
including the
包括
phenomenal and beautiful blog post by Chris Ola
克里斯·奥拉的非凡而美丽的博客文章
and the articles in distill
还有蒸馏中的文章
to close things off here for the last few minutes
在最后几分钟关闭这里的东西
I want to jump back into a snippet of the interview
我想回到采访的片段
that I had with Lisha Lee
我和丽莎·李在一起
you might remember her from the last video
你可能还记得上一段视频里的她
she did her PhD work in deep learning
她是深度学习博士
and in this little snippet
在这个小片段中
she talks about
她谈到
two recent papers
最近的两篇论文
that really dig into how some of the more modern
真正深入研究了一些更现代的
image recognition networks are actually learning
图像识别网络实际上是在学习
just to set up where we were in the conversation
只是为了确定我们在谈话中的位置
the first paper took one of these
第一篇论文拿走了其中一个
particularly deep neural networks
特别是深度神经网络
that's really good at image recognition
那真的很擅长图像识别
and
和
instead of training it on a properly labeled dataset
而不是在正确标记的数据集上训练它
it shuffled all of the labels around before training
它在训练前洗牌了所有的标签
obviously the testing
显然测试
accuracy here was going to be no better than random
这里的准确性不会比随机的好
since everything's just randomly labeled
因为所有东西都是随机标记的
but it was still able to achieve the same training
但它仍然能够达到同样的训练
accuracy as you would on a properly labeled data set
与在正确标记的数据集上一样准确
basically
基本上
the millions of weights for this particular network
这个特定网络的数百万个权重
were enough for it to just memorize the random data
足以让它记住随机数据
which kind of raises the question for whether
这就提出了一个问题
minimizing this cost function
最小化这个代价函数
actually corresponds to any
实际上对应于任何
sort of structure in the image
图像中的某种结构
or is it just you know
还是只是你知道
memorization the entire data set
记忆整个数据集
of what the correct classification is
正确的分类是什么
and so a couple of you know
所以你们中的一些人知道
half a year later at ICML this year
半年后，今年在ICML
there was not exactly rebuttal paper
没有确切的反驳文件
paper that addressed some aspects of like
涉及类似的某些方面的论文
hey actually
嘿其实
these networks are doing something
这些网络正在做一些事情
a little bit smarter
聪明一点
than that if you look at that accuracy curve
如果你看一下准确度曲线
if you were just training on a
如果你只是在训练
random data set that curve sort of went down very
随机数据集的曲线有点下降
you know
你知道的
very slowly in almost kind of a linear fashion
非常慢，几乎是线性的。
so you're really struggling to find that local minimum
所以你真的很难找到当地的最小值
of possible you know
可能你知道
the right weights that would get you that accuracy
正确的重量会让你达到这种准确性
whereas
然而
if you're actually training on a structured data set
如果您实际上是在结构化数据集上进行训练
one that has the right labels
有正确标签的
you know
你知道的
you fiddled around a little bit in the beginning
你一开始有点胡闹
but then you kind of dropped very fast to get to that
但后来你很快就学会了
accuracy level
准确度等级
and so in some sense it was
所以从某种意义上说，它是
easier to find that local maxima
更容易找到局部极大值
and so it was also interesting about that is it
所以这也很有趣，是吗？
brings into
使陷入
like another paper from actually a couple of years ago
就像几年前的另一篇论文一样
which has a lot more simplifications
它有更多的简化
about the network layers
关于网络层
but one of the results was
但结果之一是
saying how if you look at the optimization landscape
说如果你看看优化环境
the local minima that these networks tend to learn
这些网络倾向于学习的局部最小值
are actually of equal quality
实际上是同等质量的
so in some sense if your data set is structured
所以在某种意义上，如果你的数据集是结构化的
you should be able to find that much more easily
你应该能更容易地找到它
my thanks
我的感谢
as always to those of you supporting on Patreon
一如既往地支持帕特隆的人
I've said before just what a game changer on Patreon is
我之前说过Patreon的游戏规则改变者是什么
but these videos really would not be possible
但这些视频真的不可能
without you
没有你
I also want to give a special thanks to the VC firm
我还要特别感谢风投公司
Amplify Partners
放大合作伙伴
in their support of these initial videos in the series
支持该系列的这些初始视频